所以如果我想做点什么
So if I wanted to make something sleep,
这意味着我想做些类似弹跳的事情
that would mean I wanted to do
something similar to the bounce.
我想要一个在一些经过一段时间后才会执行的功能。
I want a function that's not gonna
execute until some elapsed time.
所以，在某个时候，我要用一个设定的超时，在里面的某个地方。
So at some point, I'm gonna use
a set timeout, somewhere in there.
但我想用一个承诺因为我们在用异步的等待
But I wanna use a promise
because we're using async await.
所以，让我们把它编码起来。
So let's code that up.
把你关了
Close you.
好了，再一次，我需要解决任何问题的方法
All right, so again, the method
of tackling any problem is I need
一个需要时间的功能我们会叫它睡觉
a function that takes time,
and we're gonna call it sleep.
所以功能睡眠
So function sleep, and
那就需要时间了
it's gonna take time.
我要把它长出来因为我要把这个弄坏
And I'm gonna make this long because it's,
I'm gonna break this out like this.
但本质上我们是用异步方法
But essentially because
we're using an async method,
我们知道我们想在这一特定领域做出承诺
we know we wanna use a promise
in this particular one.
所以我可以说回一个新的承诺
So I can say return a new Promise.
而普罗米塞一直都是我一直想叫它回叫
And Promises always have,
I always wanna call it a callback, but
这不是回叫
it's not a callback.
它叫做执行器，因为它最终会执行这个功能。
It's called an executor, because it will
eventually always execute this function.
它会有两个，所有的承诺都有决心和拒绝。
And it's gonna have two,
all Promises have resolve and reject.
在您设置时， hey，当返回此值时，此值是否有效或无效 ?
As in you set, hey, when this returned,
is this valid or is not valid?
但在这件案子里我们不会拒绝的
But in this case,
we're not gonna use reject.
我把它放进去了
I just put that in there for giggles.
所以我们有一个承诺，我们有一个功能。
So we have a Promise, we have a function.
这将会是个保证在某个时候会解决的
It's gonna return a Promise, and
it's gonna resolve at some point.
所以真正回归的决心
So the resolve to actually return,
就说我已经处理好了我们得调个决心
let's say I'm done processing,
we have to invoke resolve.
但我们要等 X 秒再等一下
But we wanna wait x seconds,
and how do we wait again?
>> 设置超时。
&gt;&gt; Set a time out.
>> 是，所以我要说， setTimeout。
&gt;&gt; Yes, so I'm gonna say, setTimeout.
超时，这当然需要一些功能。
Timeout, which of course
takes some function.
我们想让 setTimeout 在第二次睡眠中运行
And we want setTimeout to run for
the sleep second, so
我们希望能及时地运行
we want to run it at time.
只要花了时间我们就会解决的
And whenever the time has elapsed,
we're gonna resolve.
这就是你建立睡眠功能的方式。
And that is how you
build a sleep function.
现在，回到我们的例子，它要睡觉了，它会等着我们。
So now, going back to our example,
it's going to sleep, it's gonna wait.
我们不是在等待任何价值
We're not waiting for any value.
我们不在乎价值是什么
We don't care what the value is.
我们要等 500 毫秒
We're gonna wait 500 milliseconds.
无论我们通过什么它都要执行这个
Whatever we pass in,
it`s gonna execute this.
它会被击中的
It's gonna hit this.
还要再等 500 毫秒
It's gonna wait another 500 milliseconds.
这会打印的
It's gonna print this.
我觉得这是个不错的面试问题
I consider this a pretty
decent interview question.
它就像，你明白吗 ? 你明白吗 ?
Cuz it's like, do you understand Promises,
do you understand setTimeout?
您是否了解 Promses 是如何解决的 ?
Do you understand how
Promises get resolved?
我不太详细
Without going into too much detail.
我要问你的另一个问题
Now, the other question
I was gonna ask you, and
我不会问你这个问题很有挑战性
I'm not gonna ask you this
one cuz it's challenging,
在具有完成回调的签名的某些函数的情况下。
is, given some function that has
a signature that finishes the callback.
就像传统的 JavaScript 或者很多现代的节点功能
So kind of like old-school JavaScript,
or a lot of modern node functions,
你也能做到这一点
you can do this, too.
我如何才能让这个功能让我能说
How would I promisefy this function so
that I can say,
然后， .then. ， . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .
.then, .then, .then, .then?
我不会去那个的因为它需要一段时间才能过去
I'm not gonna go into that one because
it would take a while to go over,
但我可以让你快速的解决这个问题
but I can show you the solution real fast.
[SOUND] 回答。
[SOUND] Answers.
当你看到它的时候你就会腹股沟
And when you see it, you're gonna groan.
你会喜欢的为什么杰姆
You'll be like, why, Jem?
你为什么要这么对我们
Why would you do that to us?
有点乱但也有类似的想法
A little messy, but similar idea.
你有一个功能最终会返回一个功能
You have a function that's gonna
eventually return a function, and
当你调用它时，它会是一个 Promise ，所以你可以把它链上。
then when you invoke that, it's gonna
be a Promise, so you can chain it.
因此，它是一个函数，它具有返回另一个函数的函数和
So it's a function that takes a function
that returns another function and
返回承诺。
returns a Promise.
那个诺言是要解决的然后你就会这么说
That Promise is just gonna resolve,
and then you call that.
你把所有争论都放在一起
And you concat all the arguments together,
最后一个是回调函数。
with the last one being
the callback function.
就像你一样
Just like you would.
因此，一旦承诺解决，它就会调用回调。
So it calls the callback
once the promise resolves.
更有一种心理模型来说明你是怎么做到的
It's more of a mental model
of how you would do this
我觉得更重要的是了解它的 nitty-gritty
that I find more important than actually
understanding the nitty-gritty of it.
但忽略你看到的那个
But ignore that you saw that.
去试着让你去做点什么
Go ahead and try to promisefy something,
因为这是一个面试问题人们会问你的
because it is an interview
question people will ask you.
这可能是人们最不喜欢的事情之一。
And it's probably one of
people's least favorite things.
因为你只是，我从没想过，我怎么能让你去做点什么呢 ?
Because you just, I never thought,
how would I promisefy something?
我从来没有想过
I never gave it any thought.
所以，当你有机会的时候，请你在家里试试。
So go ahead and try that one at
home when you have a chance.